



Most Sanjida Anjum Suchi

Nationality: Bangladeshi Date of birth: 03/06/1998

Capacita Spring Spring Phone number: (+880) 1571704103

Email address: sanjidasuchi405@gmail.com

◯ WhatsApp Messenger: 01786978677

in LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/sanjida-anjum-suchi-207951241/

• Home: Bagantuli , 88/1, Shibgani Chapainawabgani, Rajshahi, 6340 Rajshahi (Bangla

desh)

ABOUT ME

I am self motivated and highly enthusiastic to learn new things. My research interest is in Remote Sensing, GIS, Geospatial Analysis, Geography, Urban Planning, Environmental Engineering, Climate Change, Environmental Impact assessment, Waste Management and Pollution Control, Environmental Policy and Planning, Natural Resource Management, Environmental Data Science.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Consultant

Center for Environmental and Geographic Information Services (CEGIS) [01/02/2023 – Current]

City: Dhaka

Country: Bangladesh

- -Managing geodatabase, prepare GIS layers and solving different problems for spatial data
- -Spatial data analysis, image interpretation, land use/cover classification maps preparation, cropping pattern extraction etc.
- -Satellite image processing, mosaicking, assessing, analyzing accurately and also working with vector data analyzing and processing.

Junior Urban Planner

Development and Design Consultants (DDC) [01/10/2022 - 30/01/2023]

City: Dhaka

Country: Bangladesh

Worked with DDC as a "Junior Urban Planner". I was appointed to the "Mouza and Plot Based National Digital Land Zoning Project" which is carried out by the Ministry of Land

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelor of Urban and Regional Planning

Khulna University of Engineering and Technology [10/01/2017 - 30/06/2022]

City: Khulna

Country: Bangladesh

Website: kuet.ac.bd/department/URP/index.php

Field(s) of study: GIS and Remote Sensing Studio | Environmental Chemistry | Statistics for Planners | Principles

of Environmental Planning | Water Resource Planning & Management | Environmental Planning and

Management | Project Planning and Management

Final grade: 3.25

Thesis: Covid-19 Impact on Women's Travel Behavior Changes & Modal Shifts

- GIS and Remote Sensing Project: A Spatiotemporal Analysis of Land-Use Changes in Rohingya Refugee Camps Using Multi-Temporal Satellite Image Analysis
- Joblessness Problem of "Ispahani Labor Colony" (Kulibagan & Sadhubagan Slum), Daulatpur, Khulna: A Participatory Planning Approach To analyze the community's social, economic and environmental issues by using PRA tools.
- Site Analysis for Neighborhood Planning and Design In this project I accomplished Site Inventory Analysis, Site Suitability Analysis, SWOT Analysis
- Environmental Profile of Ward 11 of Khulna City Corporation: The purpose of this study was to make a detail inventory of environmental component.
- Analysis the Effect of Road Characteristics on Traffic Flow Characteristics: A case study from shibbari to sonadanga road, Khulna.
- Analysis of the landscaping: Surrounding land use, networking system and modern facilities and suitability of Ishwardi Railway station.

Project "Ektee Bari Ektee Khamar" (One House, One Farm)

Khulna University of Engineering and Technology [01/04/2022 - 01/05/2022]

City: Khulna

Country: Bangladesh

Website: kuet.ac.bd/department/URP/index.php

DIGITAL SKILLS

Microsoft Office package: Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access / ArcGIS and ERDAS IMAGINE / ArcGIS, ERDAS IMAGINE 2014, Global Mapper, ILWIS, QGIS, ENVI / LiDAR Remote Sensing / Microsoft Word / GIS & Remote Sensing / Statistical analyses softwares (SPSS, R / R Studio, Amos, NVivo) / SketchUP (3D modelling) / Video Conferencing (Zoom, Teams, Skype, Webex) - Advanced / Team work orientated

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Bengali

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING B2 READING B2 WRITING B2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

PUBLICATIONS

Preparedness planning and Management: A Literature Review of Emergency Fire

[2021]

ISSN: 03875547, Volume 44, Issues 05, October 2021

Global policies on fire disaster management have highlighted individual and community responsibilities and roles in managing risk and promoting coping capacity. The establishment of local preparedness techniques is viewed as a vital element in real response and rescue.

The main purpose of the paper is to review. This review paper represents a synthesis of available literature on emergency fire disaster preparedness published between 2000 and 2020, based on eligibility criteria.

<u>The Perspective of the Bangladeshi Students About the Impact of COVID-19 On Higher Education</u> [2022]

Handbook of Research on Asian Perspective of the Educational impact of COVID-19; IGI Global, 2022

Today, there is usually a conflict about emergency remote learning (ERL) as a substitution for the formal education system. The goal of this chapter is to figure out the advantages and drawbacks of ERL, particularly for students and teachers, and assess the student's satisfaction levels on ERL due to Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19).

PROJECTS

GIS and Remote Sensing Project: A Spatiotemporal Analysis of Land-Use Changes in Rohingya Refugee Camps Using Multi-Temporal Satellite Image Analysis

[01/09/2019 - 30/11/2019]

In August 24, 2017, a massive outbreak took place in the Rakhine state of Myanmar which triggered a huge refugee influx to the Teknaf Peninsula, Bangladesh. This paper has examined the extent of vegetation change and the changes of LST from 2017 to 2019 throughout Kutupalong and Balukhali camp and adjacent areas using Landsat 8 images. Random forest algorithm and Plank equation were applied on images to identify vegetation change and LST, respectively.

ORGANISATIONAL SKILLS

Organizations of KUET Sports- OKS; Publicity & Publication Secretary

As the Publicity & Publication Secretary in OKS, I organized numerous indoor and outdoor games at the Students Welfare Center. Additionally, I coordinated events, including award ceremonies, contributing to the overall engagement and welfare of the student community.

Link: www.facebook.com/OKS.KUET/

VOLUNTEERING

Bisorgyo FORUM

[Rajshahi, Bangladesh, 01/04/2020 - Current]

This organization was involved in distribution of relief, distribution of food items, giving medicine to village people during COVID-19 crisis & still it is continuing.

TRY, A Non-Profit Voluntary Organization of KUETians

[Khulna, Bangladesh, 01/03/2017 - 01/04/2022]

The main purpose was to support underprivileged students by organizing fundraising campaigns, aiding families in times of illness, coordinating with the Alumni Association for assistance, and conducting initiatives such as distributing winter clothes, fixing houses, and providing small loans for purchasing study materials.

Link: www.facebook.com/try.kuet/

DREAM-Voluntary Blood Donation Society of KUET

[Khulna, Bangladesh, 01/03/2017 - 01/04/2022]

It has a vision for the world where no one will die in need of blood. Dream, managed by the students of KUET works to encourage the humane activity by providing blood donors. Dream work on the motto of "Donate blood, save life"

Link: www.facebook.com/DreamKuet/

HONOURS AND AWARDS

Poster Presentation - secured 1st position

Organized by Industrial production management (IEM), KUET [10/02/2019]

Poster Presentation, World Town Planning Day, Bangladesh - 1st Runner-Up

Institute of Planners [15/06/2019]

Technical Scholarship, Higher Secondary School Certificate

Ministry of Education, Intermediate and Secondary Education Boards, Bangladesh [23/05/2017]

RECOMMENDATIONS

Professor

Name: Ismail Saifullah

Phone number: (+880) 1716789402 Email: saifullah@ce.kuet.ac.bd

Department of Civil Engineering

Khulna University of Engineering & Technology (KUET)

Khulna -9203, Bangladesh.

Assistant Professor

Name: Shuvra Sikder

Phone number: (+61) 493273113 Email: shuvra@urp.kuet.ac.bd

Department of Urban and Regional Planning

Khulna University of Engineering & Technology (KUET)

Khulna -9203, Bangladesh

Assistant Professor

Name: Sharfan Upaul

Phone number: (+880) 1634872327 Email: s.upaul@urp.kuet.ac.bd

Department of Urban and Regional Planning

Khulna University of Engineering & Technology (KUET)

Khulna -9203, Bangladesh